MARK THOMAS CLAYTON

Advisor

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/markthomasclayton/

GitHub Profile: https://claytonscreations.github.io/



Safety focused Lead of Generation's Wildfire Mitigation Plan (WMP) activities with extensive experience and expertise in remediation planning, inspection process, system hardening analysis and vegetation management. Able to lead initiatives/programs and ensure success. Demonstrated skills in ArcGIS, SAP and data reporting and analytics. Strong knowledge of records management and continuous improvement tactics with advanced proficiency in Excel and PowerPoint. Recognized for the ability to successfully collaborate across Organizations at all levels. Proven history of showcasing flexibility and adaptability and excelling and exceeding expectations in fast-paced environments.

Key Skills

Leadership | Problem Solving | Communication | Teamwork | Adaptability Self-motivation | Public Speaking | Decision Making | Responsibility

Software Proficiency - SAP, Winshuttle | eDMRM (OpenText) | ArcGIS, Survey123 | Adobe Pro, Photoshop Microsoft Office (including Excel (VBA), OneDrive, Outlook, PowerPoint, Project, Publisher, SharePoint, Visio & Word) Data Analytics & Visualizations - Tools: Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & Tableau | Libraries/Databases: Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, SciPy, Plotly, D3, Leaflet, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, & Bootstrap

Experience

SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA EDISON 2005 – Present

Advisor

Asset Performance Engineering, Condition Monitoring & Analytics | Asset Mgmt & Gen Strategy

May 2017 – Present

Project manage the entire <u>Generation Wildfire Mitigation Plan (WMP)</u> which includes asset inspections, remediations, vegetation management, and system hardening activities.

- Coordinated the completion of over 400 inspections across SCE Territory including training field crews and technicians and provided regular updates to senior leadership throughout the organization.
- Reviewed all inspection data and processed notifications to field crews to reduce and remediate possible ignition risks. Ensured remediation of all findings within compliance deadlines.
- Managed and supported Advisor's to ensure execution and compliance of the Expanded Clearance vegetation project and analysis of 9 hydro control circuits.
- Led the cross coordination between Generation and T&D to remove 3 unsafe Agnew transmission towers.
- Project managed the grounding studies and lightning arrestor assessments of 33 sites and coordinated mitigation action identified by vendor.
- Led low voltage site analysis that identified sites across the territory for ways to reduce ignition risk such as battery/solar conversions, covered conductor, or other ignition reduction opportunities.
- Collaborated with WMP leads and departments to develop project plans, goals, and milestones. Often respond
 to requests from regulatory agencies like the CPUC/WSD.

Manage the <u>Gen-T&D Roles and Responsibilities Alignment (RRA)</u> which includes coordinating meetings with the Union and key stakeholders on changes.

- Developed project plan to replace the Catalina Transformers to improve reliability of power and reduce point of failure.
- Oversaw the Generation Maintenance update process to incorporated existing technology that reduced costs associated with purchasing and integrating new systems.
- Compliance liaison between 3 OUs to streamline coordination and communications.
- Worked with the Generation Diversity and Inclusion action team to develop a hiring guide to assist Managers
 in taking steps necessary to attracting and hiring a diverse workforce.

- Completed my yellow belt certification courses and 2 kaizen continuous improvement events. I continue to stay certified by completing a minimum of 1 kaizen every 6 months.
- Managed SAP requests such as developing job aids, creating processes, maintenance plan creation, FLOC/Equip updates, data pulls and comparisons that require pivot tables, vlook-up and matching exercises.
- Assisted project manage the Penstock Inspections Program by acting as a field rep. for contractors, collecting engineering data, providing scheduling assistance, and reviewing timesheets and purchase order documents.
- Redesigned 15 Portal (SharePoint Intranet) pages reducing scrolling/clicking by an average of 50%.

Program/Project Analyst 3

Documents & Records Management | Asset Management & Generation Strategy

November 2015 - May 2017

Responsible for documents and records management for Generation Organization by acting as the Information Steward, managing the annual review, and dispositioning of records, planning, and executing records clean-up events, and being the Point of Contact for questions.

- Pulled from regular duties to lead the process and procedures activity for the new Asset Management Program
 being developed to ensure proper development and storage of newly created documents.
- Worked closely with IT and our clients to identify, classify, and move documents from shared folders to
 eDMRM. Continued to be the administrator of those libraries to help clients when retrieving and storing
 business records as well as managing access.
- **Led a segment of a drawing project** which incorporated analyzing data to determine which records were outdated and subsequently worked with a vendor on validation and updates that decreased errors.

Construction Material Coordinator 1

Corporate Drawing Management | Records Management & Information Governance

April 2010 – November 2015

Responsible for records management data related to the engineering documents library 'CRT Dashboard' and user interface 'CDM Library' which are used by multiple departments and vendors for construction projects.

- **Processed engineering documents / drawings** by completing a quality check of drawings, data entry of key elements, electronic scanning, and distribution of the engineering package.
- Key project team member during the design and implementation of new engineering documents library CRT Dashboard and user interface CDM Library.
- Updated the Business Continuity process for all emergency hard drives and decreased the time to update, developed a schedule to reduce time away from sites and developed better tracking forms.
- Managed confidential documents and materials such as Critical Energy Infrastructure Information (CEII) and North American Reliability Corporation, Critical Infrastructure Protection (NERC CIP).

Began career at SCE as a Student Utility Worker (2005 – 2006) and Customer Service Representative (2006 – 2010)

Education

Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization, UC Irvine	March 2022
The Leverage Effect Certificate, UC Irvine, Paul Merage School of Business	December 2020
Yellow Belt Certification, Southern California Edison Internal Training Program	September 2019
The Dynamic Leader Certificate, UC San Diego, Rady School of Management	November 2018
Project Management Certificate, University of Phoenix	March 2016
AutoCAD Essentials Certificate, Autodesk	February 2016
The Innovative Leader Certificate, UC San Diego, Rady School of Management	June 2015
The Strategic Leader Certificate, UC San Diego, Rady School of Management	May 2014

Of Note Activities

Generation Office Safety Congress (SCE)

Elected Team Lead

October 2017 - December 2020

<u>Led the Generation Office Safety Congress</u> with team members from across our territory to improve the office safety culture and served as a safety resource to assist employees with a variety of safety items.

- Awarded the 2020 Safety Honor Award which is the highest safety recognition given annually to only 30 employees with outstanding performance or behavior in safety.
- **Planned an Emergency Kit Building Contest** event for Generation, Customer Service, & HR that was attended by 273 employees, had 17 contest submissions, and provided over 100 cases of emergency waters.
- Certified in First Aid/CPR/AED by Red Cross and trained as a Tier 2 Ergo specialist to assist as a resource when ergonomic issues were escalated from a manager.
- Led projects that won an annual Corporate Triple Crown Award for:
 - Designed and implemented an improvement to the emergency response role assignments during meetings by creating cones that serve as a visual representation of the assignment. (2nd Place 2019)
 - o Coordinated with Corporate Safety to develop a new mobile ergo lab presentation for field employees at their office to improve ergonomics and show products they can order. (1st Place 2018)
 - o **Improved the incidental use of first aid supplies** by attaching a magnetic box with the 4 most used items, this kept us OSHA Compliant and reduced costs of replacing kits. (1st Place 2017)

Lighthouse Business Resource Group (SCE)

President, Vice President, Program Director, Event Director & Ally Chair

January 2009 - June 2020

Served on the Board of Director's in various capacities with the goal to engage Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender and Ally (LGBT+) employees in personal and professional growth by providing opportunities for education, networking, mentoring, and community involvement. Recognized as a resource and advocate for LGBT+ issues.

- Program Director and Ally Chair from 2017-2020 that led the effort to expand the Ally 101 program from 1 course into a series of 9 courses and trained presenters.
 - o Program was delivered over 30 times to different groups including the SCE Senior Leadership Team.
 - o Designed, created, and relaunched the Safe Space Program in 2010.
- Served as Event Director from 2015-2017 and coordinated numerous fundraising and volunteer events that equaled to hundreds of hours of volunteer work and donating over \$25,000 to non-profit organizations.
 - Planned and executed numerous networking / career development events with Executives that included the catering, entertainment, main program, ticket sales, giveaways and more.
- Elected President and Vice President from 2009-2014 and was able to rebuild and repair a bad reputation, develop best practices, implement new programs and events all while increasing memberships.